# **Michael Martinson**

**%** 714 604 8818

Orange County, CA

One year of experience as a Software Developer Engineer at Amazon. I am eager to learn something new and challenge myself. I am not scared of failure because I know failure is just an opportunity to learn and improve. If I lack knowledge to solve a problem I am condent that I can quickly gain the skills necessary to solve it. I would say that my strengths are: fast learner, persistent, hard worker, team player, passionate, optimistic, eager.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, **University of Chicago** Varsity Student-Athelete with Cumulative GPA 3.5/4.00 Honors: Dean's List, Academic All-Conference Expected June 2021

## **Technical Skills**

Language Proficiency

• Python, C, Javascript, HTML, CSS, React

## **Work Experience**

Software Development Engineer Intern, Amazon

June 2020-August 2020

 Gained experience using Javascript, React, HTML, and CSS developing alexa skills.

Software Developer Intern, Center For Translational Data Science

June 2019-June 2020

 Gained experience using Python, Flask, and HTTP requests. Worked with a team using the Agile Framework

## **Projects**

Python SDK - Center For Translational Data Science

 Created a software development kit for users and developers using gen3 data commons to hit a data commons api endpoints using python rather than using the UI

Project Cache - University of Chicago

• Built a C program to simulate a cache given number of sets, number of lines in each set, and block size then return the number of hits, misses, and evictions

#### Extracurricular

Varsity Football - University of Chicago, Running Back

• Balanced a 20+ hour weekly commitment to football with full academic course load. I developed skills in leadership, teamwork, time management, and resilience

August 2017-Present

Fellowship of Christian Athletes - University of Chicago, President/Member

• Coordinate and organize weekly meetings and club events. An example of an event that we run is blanket making for kids in childrens hospitals.

October 2019-Present

#### Interests

• Football, Board Games, Video Games, Cooking, Learning, Game Development, Hiking, Surng